barclaycard.co.uk 2019-05-09

# Barclaycard Privacy and Cookie Policy | Barclaycard

## Privacy Policy

This policy applies to information we hold about you.  In this policy, 'we', 'us', and 'our' mean Barclaycard, which is a trading name of Barclays Bank UK PLC., registered number 9740322, registered office 1 Churchill Place, London E14 5HP. Barclaycard’s trading address is at 1234 Pavilion Drive, Northampton NN4 7SG.  'You' means the person the information relates to.

This policy applies to information held about customers and possible future customers, suppliers and possible future suppliers, contacts and all other people we hold information about.  By ‘information’ we mean personal and financial information about you that we collect, use, share and store. For further details on the information about you that we may process, please see the full Barclaycard Privacy Policy PDF (339KB).

### How we collect information about you

We collect, use, share and store information about you to provide you with the services that you have requested from us and to share information with you about services that may be of interest to you.  We will collect your information directly from you or from third parties.  For further details of where we may obtain your information from, see the full Barclaycard Privacy Policy PDF (339KB).

### How we use your information

We use this information:

  * to provide our services to you;
  * to help us develop new and improved products and services to meet our customers' needs;
  * for security and to check your identity; 
  * for training;
  * to communicate with you;
  * to comply with legal and regulatory obligations;
  * where we have a legitimate interest in doing so, such as the protection of our business interests or the prevention of fraud; and
  * to keep you informed about products and services you hold with us and to send you information about products or services (including those of other companies that may be of interest to you).

We will use automated processes. For further information, including the legal basis on which we use your information, please see the full Barclaycard Privacy Policy PDF (339KB).

### Sharing your information with others

We’ll keep your information confidential but we may share it in certain circumstances, for the purposes set out in this policy, with:

  * other Barclays companies;
  * other companies who provide a service to you, for example if you use our products to make a purchase or payment;
  * any company we are providing services with or whose name or logo appears on our products;
  * our service providers and agents, including their subcontractors;
  * social media companies so that they can display messages to you about our products and services; 
  * anyone we transfer or may transfer our rights, duties, debts or assets to;
  * credit reference agencies; and
  * fraud prevention agencies who will use it to prevent fraud and money-laundering and to verify your identity. If fraud is detected, you could be refused certain services, finance or employment.

The people and organisations listed above will also have to keep it secure and confidential.

For further details of third parties we may share your information with, and how your information will be used by us, fraud prevention agencies, credit reference agencies, and other third parties, see the full Barclaycard Privacy Policy PDF (339KB).  

### Credit Reference Agencies and Fraud Prevention Agencies

We will supply your personal information to credit reference agencies and fraud prevention agencies and they will give us information about you, such as about your financial history. We do this to assess creditworthiness and product suitability, check your identity, manage your account, trace and recover debts and prevent criminal activity. These agencies may in turn share your personal information with other organisations. If fraud is detected, you could be refused certain services, finance or employment.

If false or inaccurate information is provided to us and fraud is identified, details may be passed to credit reference and fraud prevention agencies to prevent fraud and money laundering and to verify your identity.

The Credit Reference Agency Information Notice (CRAIN) describes how the three main credit reference agencies in the UK each use and share personal data. The CRAIN is available on the credit reference agencies’ websites:

Or you can ask us for a copy of these.

For more details on how information held by credit reference agencies and fraud prevention agencies may be used, please see the full Barclaycard Privacy Policy PDF (339KB).  

### Your rights

You have rights relating to the way that we use your information, and can make certain choices. For example, you can:

  * inform us of a correction to your personal data;
  * withdraw any permission you have previously given to allow us to use your information;
  * object to any automated decision-making;
  * ask us to stop or start sending you marketing messages; 
  * ask us to send you (or someone you nominate) a copy of the information we hold about you;
  * ask us to stop using your information in certain circumstances.

To use any of the rights set out above, or to discuss any other issue relating to your information, please contact us via the methods set out in the 'Contact us' section.

If you have any concerns about the way we use your information, you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner's Office, which regulates the use of personal information in the UK, by calling [0303 123 1113](tel:03031231113 "Call the ICO on 0303 123 1113") or via [www.ico.org.uk/make-a-complaint/](https://ico.org.uk/make-a-complaint/ "View the Information Commissioner's Office website, opens in a new window, third party site").

For further details on your rights concerning the way we use your information, and other ways to contact us, please see the full Barclaycard Privacy Policy PDF (339KB).  

### Contact us

Please go to [www.barclays.co.uk/control-your-data](https://www.barclays.co.uk/important-information/control-your-data/ "View Barclays control your data page, opens in a new window") if you have any questions about privacy issues. If you would like more information on your rights, or you want to exercise them, please send a request through our website at [www.barclays.co.uk/control-your-data](https://www.barclays.co.uk/important-information/control-your-data/ "View Barclays control your data page, opens in a new window").

You can contact our data protection officer at: The Data Protection Officer, Barclays Bank UK PLC, Leicester, LE87 2BB or email: [DPO@Barclays.com](mailto:DPO@Barclays.com "Email the Barclays data protection officer").  

### Changes to personal data law

In May 2018, the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) will change the law in regard to your personal data. Explore [www.barclays.co.uk/control-your-data](https://www.barclays.co.uk/important-information/control-your-data/ "Visit Barclays GDPR Page, opens in a new window") to see how it affects you. It includes updates to our privacy notices to reflect your rights in relation to personal data, and the legal grounds for using it.  

### Important information about Payment Protection Insurance (PPI)

If you’re looking for information about PPI, you don’t need to submit a subject access request. You can ask us to check if you’ve had or have PPI, or make a complaint about it, for free.

Visit our PPI page

### Security

Please remember that any messages you send over the internet aren't secure unless they are encrypted. We’re not responsible for unauthorised access by a third party or the corruption of any information sent to us.

So for your own security, please don't send us any personal or account information by standard email.
